this is my client Nicole osoria you can
find her on Instagram here we're going
to take you through a home glute workout
using just body weight and band
exercises so first up we got the skater
squat so in the past I've I haven't
recommended skater squats a lot because
if you don't have support you feel more
in the quads but when you use
support and you just used as much as you
need sink back reach back this is a very
glute dominant movement so we're
starting off with skater
squats and I would probably just you
know have Nicole do around three sets of
10 now you could say how to use
Progressive overload with this movement
that's a good point because she's giving
herself assistance you really don't know
if you're getting stronger over time
switch legs
but you're going to feel this in the
glutes a lot reach back sink into that
hip and the goal is to get deeper over
time and to use less
assistance if you have a partner with
you you can obviously
just hold their
hands like
that reach back good so three sets of 10
okay so that's exercise number
one all right next up we're going
deficit split squats so Nicole is going
to sink way down deep come back up
trying to really trying to really
stretch the
glutes now this will also work the quads
and the
adductors the goal is to go really
really deep
again probably three sets of 10 would
be a good goal for this
one now these two services are roughly
level you could have the back foot a
little higher and have it more like a
rear foot elevator a Bulgarian split
squat but anything that lets you sink
extra deep that's the goal here
next up we have the single leg hip
thrust now I give this in my booty by
breath program all the time three sets
of 20 put your arms out straight out
come down tap your butt to the ground
come up leg there you want it out of the
way tap your butt a little faster three
is that three four we're going to do 20
here
five tap
six seven
eight I'm actually showing the 20 reps
nine because three sets of 20 is brutal
in my booty B rep program it's a
LoveHate relationship um and I give this
as an option if you don't want to do
barbell hip thrust but yeah 3X 20 with
like did you do 20 you did not do 20 CAU
we will count those out 15 okay she was
at Nicole is acting all tough today
brutal yeah she was acting tough cuz no
one does sing like hip thrust okay two
let's get 15
6 I mean I did 15 already wait are you
drunk give me a
second I can do with the other leg
whenever you're at home I promise you
three sets of 20 hip thrust with like a
minute rest in between if you can do
that then you're awesome because it is
really really hard to do um I I've done
it before 3x2 just to like experience
what my clients go through and that's
really hard for me and I can hip thrust
I've hip thrusted 800 lb so don't think
that you're above single leg hip thrust
make sure you tap your butt to the
ground and come all the way up into full
hip extension just like Nicole is doing
here push the heel we want the shin at a
vertical uh Shin vertical at the top 90°
knee
angle and see how she kind of rock rocks
back in hinges with single leg hypos we
always do hinge method never scoop
method meaning what that means is don't
look forward and move from the sternum
down we don't ever do single leg hip
thrust like this it still works just not
as good as the hinge method where you
rock back and push as tall as possible
okay
good next up we have dual elevated knee
expanded hip dust this is the best glute
exercise that you're not doing so Nicole
is going to put her arms out put her
feet on top of the you kind of got to if
you do this right you'll feel kind of
cramped together here so then she's
going to go down and touch her butt to
the ground now come down hold on come
down here's where I want her to break
the band you got to break the band when
you're at the bottom when you're at the
top I don't want you trying to push out
only push out right at the bottom now
when you come up let your knees come in
and push tall Rock tall boom yep now out
Boom come up now from here pause pause
she's not trying to push out here in
fact let your knees come in and like
push as tall as you can go boom that's
the lock out from here as soon as you
start going down I want to see this
spread Spread spread and when your butt
touches the ground it reaches its its
widest
point so and then you got to make sure
this table doesn't slide I'm going to
sit on it yeah keep going okay spread
Spread spread nope I did not see it
spread okay come up on the way up on the
way down so start spreading on the way
down right there out yes good come up
tall knees
out push tall so when you do this right
you'll feel extra glute activation at
the bottom of the hip thrust um the
reason why this works so good I'm just
going to try to explain the science real
quick when you're in deep hip flexion
the bottom of a squat lunge hip thrust
you name it gluto activation reduces for
some reason when you're doing hip
extension at the bottom it could be
related to the moment arm The Leverage
of the muscle the nervous system does
not activate it very highly but when you
push out the glutes activate way higher
so same stretch same range of motion
with more glute activation has to result
in Greater glute growth so even though
you don't have a lot of load on your
hips in fact you have no load on your
hips just load at the knees this does
provide a big challenge to the glutes in
fact you might want to start off with
three sets of 12 and then over time work
your way up to three sets of 20 you're
going to love
these all right next up just band
Kickbacks you'll see as you do these
that Nicole without even being told she
naturally turns her foot out uh at and
range hip extension that's exactly what
I want to see you can go straight back
you can go at a slight angle if you want
but it you do see a natural turnout of
the
feet as you lock out the movement so 20
reps both legs three sets of
20 this is all glutes you're not going
to feel this anywhere else
okay so next up we have the extra range
hip hike knee banded but Nicole actually
has the bands around halfway up her
thigh we hike these up okay so she's
kind of going back into a little lunge
tapping but I want what I want her to do
is sink kind of sink this way turn in
come out boom now you don't have to tap
you don't have to squat you could just
kind of stand up right and just sink
down here and come up raise out
boom so what we're looking for
is tilt the pelvis laterally and then
tilt it the other way at the lock out so
we want a glute media stretch at the
bottom and a squeeze at the
top and try to do these the way you feel
the
most see
how Nicole is kind of cursing back as
she does
these this might be the way she likes
the most but you might like going
straight straight down no not no don't
stay lateral stay frontal plane just
sink come up
boom sink
down
yeah all right that's it that's a wrap
just six exercises which is a lot if she
did three sets I'd be 18 sets which
would be hard to recover from if she
trained glutes Monday Wednesday Friday
or 3 days a week one of the biggest
problems I see with the way people train
their glutes is doing too much volume
when you're training glutes 3 days a
week like I'm always in the gym telling
my girls call it quits you got to be you
got to come back in two days you know
it's Monday Wednesday's coming around
the corner soon you don't want to be too
fatigued you need to be recovered to
have good glute workout so if we think
of the rule of thirds and the different
categories we did our kind of like our
hinge movement the skater squat it's a
squat but it's kind of like a hinge
because you sit back so much it's really
hard to do hinges with body weight
because you need a dumbbell um so that's
as hinge as it gets in my opinion the
braced skater squat then we did the
deficit split squat that's a squat lung
category then we did the single leg hip
thrust which is the thrust Bridge
category and then we followed it up with
dual elevated knee banded uh hip thrust
which it's a hip thrust but it's also
abduction especially at the bottom when
you're trying to break the band there
you're in deep hip flection that's
transverse plain hip abduction followed
up with Kickbacks which is I guess you
could categorize it as a hinge but it's
kind of its own category and then we
finished off with the extra range hip
hikes which you can do with or without a
band you can do it with ankle weights
but that's frontal plane hip abduction
so we hit the glutes from all angles we
hit the glute medius we hit the upper
glute Max we hit the lower glute Max but
I hope this video teaches you that you
can get a good highquality glute workout
in from home if you're at a hotel if
your gym is closed if you just are
stressed and can't make it to the gym
try this workout it's a lot harder than
you thought I know Nicole probably
underestimated I told her earlier she's
like I'm going to the gym to do my real
workout I'm like this workout will be
tough I know during the single hip
thrust for example were more challenging
than she anticipated I hope you like the
video make sure to hit like give it a
thumbs up if you did like it please
leave me a comment and tell me what
you'd like to see in the future and
finally make sure you're subscribed to
my channel I'm committed
2025 I'm trying to come out with a video
at least once every 5 to seven days and
big thanks to Nicole osoria
I and I said